YOU ARE HERE
Koichi…
I'm over here, Koichi.
Ah! R-Rohan Kishibe!
Hey, hey. Don't be so defensive.
My days of harming you are over.
Besides, reading your history
with Heaven's Door
filled me with
a sense of respect for you.
It's as if we're two peas in a pod.
Wouldn't you agree?
Uh…
So, I'd like to ask you
a little question.
You see, until I was about four,
I called this area home.
And I've been looking
for my old place.
You could call it nostalgia,
if you will.
Recalling childhood is central
to a manga artist's work.
But they're memories
of a three-to-four-year-old.
It's all a bit foggy.
Oh…
My question is about this town map.
It's really quite peculiar.
CONVENIENCE STORE OWSON
KISARA DRUGSTORE
SOBA SHOP ARISUGAWA
TAILOR TANAKA
Ponder this.
Here you can see
the Soba Shop Arisugawa,
Kisara Drugstore,
and the Owson convenience store
situated right-to-left.
Huh?
Now look at
the physical shops themselves.
From the right, you can see
the Soba Shop Arisugawa,
Kisara Drugstore, and…
Owson on the left…
Huh?
The map shows no road between
the Owson and the drugstore.
How sloppy…
Koichi, will you tag along?
I would be forever in your debt
if you could show me around.
Huh? Well, I, uh…
And here I, Rohan Kishibe,
went the extra mile
to ask with the utmost courtesy.
I see.
So you can't bring yourself
to show me around for a few meters.
He sure is self-centered. Jeez…
I have five minutes, okay, Sensei?
Just five minutes!
EPISODE 17
ROHAN KISHIBE'S ADVENTURE
Strange isn't it?
Even my official Shoin Press
1/3000-scale map of Morioh
makes absolutely no mention
of this street.
Huh? Sometimes if you find
a map error,
you can get
a bookstore gift certificate.
Ugh…
Blast it, this map is hopeless.
Look, Koichi.
YONEMORI
This map doesn't call out
HONMA
the "Yonemori," "Honma,"
or "Onodera" residence either.
ONODERA
NUMAKURA
This map is riddled
with oversights.
They're going to owe me
a lot more than
two or three gift certificates.
Rohan-sensei..
The place looks abandoned.
ROCKY
What a weird area.
The five or so houses around here
look completely unoccupied.
Even the vending machines are off.
Huh?
That mailbox…
We made our first turn
at this corner.
Too weird…
We're right back where we started.
But we turned right,
left, then right…
Someone could be attacking us
with their Stand.
Huh? Stand?!
Koichi, do me a favor and deploy
Reverb into the sky above us.
Of course!
From above, it'll know
exactly where we need to go.
Reverb Act 1!
What's wrong?
Something was up there.
Something grazed Reverb.
I couldn't see anything.
I know something
came in contact with Reverb!
Are you two lost?
I'd be happy to be your guide.
A girl!
That girl's a Stand user!
Heaven's Door!
Without further ado…
I shall seize victory, post haste!
BOOM
We should be safe now.
She won't be able to harm us.
Amazing!
I-It's like you launched
your drawing into mid air…
I suppose I've made some progress.
Though it doesn't work on artless
Rohan-manga haters like Josuke.
She and I are on
the same wavelength.
She's not a Stand user.
She's an ordinary girl.
Huh? So she's not out to get us?
Correct. Nothing can
hide from Heaven's Door.
Her name is Reimi Sugimoto,
aged 16.
Her address is 3-12,
Kotodai, Morioh.
That's not far from here.
She has no boyfriend.
Her bust/waist/hip are
82-57-84 centimeters.
Beside her left nipple
is a single mole.
She had her first period
the month of September, age 11.
Her first time kissing a boy,
he rammed his tongue
down her throat.
Just a minute, Rohan Kishibe!
If that girl's not a Stand user,
then I refuse to allow you
to read any further!
All right, all right.
Simmer down.
"I will forget everything
that just happened." There.
I'd be happy to be your guide.
This area trips up a lot of people.
A lot of these alleys
look the same.
Please point us
in the right direction
and we'll be on our way.
Absolutely not.
Simple explanation won't cut it.
I'll be your guide. Follow me.
Want one?
You sure?
Then go ahead and grab that end.
SNAP
Uh-oh, some girl's gonna dump you.
Who is this girl?
It's Pocky fortune-telling.
The break gives me insight
into you and your future.
Well, you are self-centered, right?
And you tend to push
people's buttons.
That's why you'll get dumped.
Hear that, Koichi?
Now we know she's totally off base!
Me, self-centered?!
Well, two can play at this game.
Light pink nail polish
means you're afraid of love.
When push comes to shove,
you let love
slip through your fingers.
Huh?
No way…
This isn't so much fortune-telling
as it is psychological prodding.
Regardless of love,
something else unnerves you.
It's said this house…
was the scene of
a murder fifteen years ago.
A murder?!
Murder…
No one lives there now.
Do you wish to hear the story?
The old lady next door
once told me.
The day it happened,
at the dead of night,
while the young girl
was asleep in her bedroom,
she awoke to a strange dripping
coming from her parents' room.
The sound puzzled the girl,
who then called out to her parents,
but there was no reply.
But the girl wasn't
particularly scared, because…
She was accompanied
by her trusty dog.
Trusty dog?
Yes. He was a great big guard dog.
In the pitch-dark, she would offer
her hand to him under the bed,
and there was always
a whimper and a lick.
Arnold was her reassurance.
But the dripping continued
for several minutes…
Finally, her curiosity
got the best of her.
She investigated, then…
There was Arnold, throat slashed,
and hanging from the coat rack.
And there was his blood dripping,
PLIP-plop.
Then, suddenly, there was
a voice from under the bed.
"Your hand is so sweet and tender,
Sweetheart. Whimper, whimper…"
"I already murdered
Mommy and Daddy." And then…
He murdered the girl, too!
I-Is that a true story?!
Sounded real, huh?
That's for that nail-polish
wisecrack.
Whew…
My heart can't take
stuff like that… Jeez…
DRIP
Wha—
That's…
Yes… That girl was me.
We're ghosts. Both Arnold and I.
G-Ghosts?
Heaven's Door read only
her living memories.
I had no idea.
You two've entered the area
where I died fifteen years ago.
I guess we're on
the same wavelength.
This is the gateway
between the living and the dead.
REVERB
Run, Koichi!
I-It's no use!
Summon Reverb, Koichi!
It can show us the way from above!
She must've been the one who
made contact with Reverb up there.
Never mind,
just get him up there, Koichi!
Wha—
What?! A wall appeared in the sky!
K-Koichi, that's the ground.
Huh?! Ah, what?!
Y-You're the one in the air.
There's only one way
out of this place.
And I know where it is.
H-How the heck
do you fight a ghost?
Please don't possess us!
Hold your horses.
Stop treating me
like some kind of vengeful spirit.
What did I do to you?
You've done a fine job
of scaring yourselves!
I didn't trap you guys here.
We're standing between the world
of the living and the dead.
You two hold some kind
of strange power, don't you?
They're called Stands?
Maybe that's what
got you mixed up in all this.
So you're not against us?
You really are suspicious,
aren't you?
I guess I'm proof
of that Stone Tape theory.
Once a ghost,
I became bound to this place.
Here, for fifteen years,
I've pleaded with
passersby to listen.
To let me share my story.
But you two are
the first people to really listen.
I told you I'd help you
get out of here,
so that's what I'll do.
After I finish the story, that is.
Story?
As I was saying…
Before I could see
the murderer's face,
I was stabbed in the back.
It was late and very dark,
and I was desperately trying
to get away.
The murderer is still loose.
He's somewhere here in Morioh.
That's what I wanted to say.
He's assimilated into
Morioh society.
Wait. Are you telling us because…
I'm not asking you to catch him.
But I want you to tell someone…
Tell the police…
Anyone who can catch him…
Hey, why should that be
our responsibility?
Rohan-sensei!
It's all right.
I'm trying to remain level-headed.
I'm sorry your life
was cut tragically short…
Still, why must we
find the murderer to appease
your feelings of resentment?
Letting go of this world,
and moving onto the next
would be a much more fitting
existence for a ghost.
Do you have any idea
how many boys and girls
have gone missing from this town?
Huh? No.
It's eight times
the national average.
And some of them
are being slaughtered in silence.
By him.
W-Wait a second!
You mean these murders
are still happening?
Hey! You can't
throw around allegations!
You said you didn't even catch
a glimpse of the murderer's face!
How would you know that?
The souls of those
murdered dominate these skies!
Their wounds are just like mine.
It's horrifying…
Such a deep gash…
I can't communicate
with those souls
making their way to the Other Side,
but over and over I witness them.
I know his obsession! I know!
Morioh,
my birthplace, my hometown,
has for fifteen years
stood in the shadow of murder.
It's terrifying,
and it's humiliating.
When they catch him,
my cherished Morioh
will be known across
Japan as that butcher's town.
But it doesn't change that
we must stop him as fast as we can!
He's preying on someone
as we speak,
and there's nothing I can do.
Who will he kill next?
If you and your beating hearts
won't take back Morioh's
peace and dignity,
then I'd like to know who will?!
I hope you took in what I said…
I have nothing more to say.
I did. I'm shocked.
I know… we have to do something.
Hmph. I wouldn't be
too big-hearted, Koichi.
It all spells trouble.
But the murderer could
be a good source of inspiration.
It might make for
some interesting manga!
Can we get out this way?
If you think he's good at heart…
Well, don't.
And when it comes to
trustworthiness,
he's shady at best.
Hey, are you listening?
All right. I'll show you
how to get to the exit.
Huh? The exit? Where? Where is it?
If you go past the mail box
and turn left, it's right there.
Yes!
Don't rush it!
There's a rule
to making it through.
A rule?
Once you make your turn past
the mail box,
you'll see the exit
about 20 meters away.
No matter what happens,
promise me you'll never look back.
Why? What for?
It's the rule for passing
from this world to the next.
Even Arnold understands that.
Well, if a dog can handle it,
I guess I can too.
And if we look back?
Your souls will be dragged into
the next world.
Death will take hold.
Don't be scared!
Just keep looking forward.
Simple, right?
When we passed the mail box…
Something flew past
our legs and went behind us!
Remember, you mustn't look back!
Just stay calm and collected.
R-Rohan-sensei,
something's creeping up behind us.
I know.
Something's there…
Something's right by my head!
Ignore it!
Something will always
try to make you look back.
As long as you
don't look back at it,
it can't touch you.
Don't let it get to you.
N-Now something warm
and runny is oozing down my neck…
Almost there!
That light is the way out.
- Huh?
- What?
Th-The exit…
I can't take it anymore!
Rohan-sensei, let's run!
Don't panic!
It'll try to trip you.
You're safe now.
You made it.
Now you can turn around.
That was terrifying!
Thank goodness it's over!
That was a lie, Koichi!
That wasn't me who said that!
Huh?
Impossible…
Not yet. You can't turn around yet.
This didn't happen when
I was by myself.
They didn't try to trick me!
Koichi!
I don't quite understand it,
but no peeking
and we're through, right?
You're lucky I'm with you, Koichi.
Heaven's Door!
You'll lose your ability to see,
then fly through the air.
CRASH
BOOM
You can calm down, Koichi.
I'll reinscribe your ability
to see shortly.
The alley between the convenience
store and drugstore is gone.
W-We're finally back…
This is where we'll stay.
Until he's apprehended.
Arnold and I will finally look back
and return to Mom and Dad,
when peace and dignity
once again returns to Morioh.
Until that day, I cannot leave.
If you ever want to talk,
about anything,
don't hesitate to come back.
I'll be here,
Rohan darling, Mr. Koichi…
From the bottom of my heart,
thank you for listening
to my story.
To think that girl
called me "Rohan darling."
Fairly presumptious, if you ask me.
But… Reimi Sugimoto, huh…
That spirit's demeanor…
it's something to be respected.
For fifteen years,
she's been waging
a solitary fight for the living.
FAMILY MASSACRE CASE
REMAINS MYSTERY
SUGIMOTO FAMILY GRAVE
SUGIMOTO
REIMI
There! Sugimoto Reimi, age 16.
Not that I doubted her,
but now I've got evidence.
Ah, you wouldn't happen to be…
Rohan Kishibe, the manga artist?
SUGIMOTO FAMILY GRAVE
Do I know you?
Rohan, you were only four,
It doesn't surprise me
you have no recollection.
Your house was
very close to theirs.
The night of the incident,
urgent business took your parents
away for the evening…
Your parents and
the Sugimotos were very close,
so they left you
with them for a single night.
That night, Rohan,
you stayed at the Sugimoto's house.
You were the only one rescued.
I was… there?
Once in police custody,
you repeated over
and over through the tears:
"Auntie Reimi snuck me
out the window."
Reimi saved you before
the murderer could find you.
That little girl…
No wonder she acted so familiar.
So Heaven's Door
gives me no insight
into my distant memories
or personal fate.
If you ever find yourself
in the alley of this story,
never, ever, look back.
MORIOH LANDMARK 6
"GHOST ALLEY"
HOW TO GET THERE: TAKE #11 BUS
FROM MORIOH STATION
TO KOTODAI SHOPPING DISTRICT.
THE ALLEY LIES BETWEEN
THE OWSON CONVENIENCE STORE
AND KISARA DRUGSTORE AT 2-CHOME.
BEWARE: IF YOU ARE ONE OF THE FEW
WHO CAN SEE THE ALLEY AND
HAPPEN TO WANDER INTO ITS DEPTHS,
DO NOT LOOK BACK, NO MATTER WHAT.
I really did meet a ghost!
- The girl in that picture is Reimi!
- Okay, we get it.
- So, I did a little research,
- I said I believe you.
- And it turns out she was a student
- At Bodogaoka High School, too.
- She's cute… Just my type.
If only I'd been born
fifteen years earlier.
Eventually, we should
probably meet this ghost, too.
You know, Koichi, if we tell Jotaro
or Mr. Joseph about any of this,
you can bet
they'll have one question:
"Is the murderer a Stand user?"
W-Well… I don't know…
Then it's up to the police
and judges.
A murderer's loose in Morioh!
I know. I'm saying Jotaro
and the Speedwagon Foundation
won't just go after
some ordinary murderer.
Try to relax.
He's managed to completely evade
the all-powerful police
for over a decade and a half.
It's not like we'd
run into the guy,
like grabbing some taxi
around here.
Let's stay calm and
look into things carefully.
So what'd 'ol Rohan have to say?
Same as you, Josuke.
Hey, be careful, Koichi.
You gotta be alert
when you cross the road.
S-Sorry…
A long time ago, Morioh was
a summer escape for samurai.
My ancestors were among them.
But then it all went south
with my grandfather.
All that's left is
the house I live in now.
And of course
my miserable little office job.
Hey, what happened to that nice
import watch I bought you?
Ah, it's in your bag.
How could I forget?
It was a little loose on you.
Tomorrow we'll get it fixed.
What's wrong? Why so coy?
Now… Watch your step.
Come, a magnificent weekend awaits.
Just the two of us.
You're dripping…
Quite ill-mannered, I must say.
I expect you to clean
that up yourself.
I can't recall your name,
but no matter.
Bravo. You tidied it up well.
Now, then…
You and I should make dinner.
What, pray tell,
is your culinary strong suit?
KIRA
EPISODE 18
SHIGECHI'S HARVEST, PART 1